<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Best Practices on Artsy Engineering</title>
    <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/best-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Best Practices on Artsy Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Great Outage Post-Mortems</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/11/19/how-to-write-great-outage-post-mortems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/11/19/how-to-write-great-outage-post-mortems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The website is finally back up after crashing hard for 4 hours straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently AWS decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/ec2-maintenance-update&#34;&gt;reboot a few of your servers for a critical update&lt;/a&gt;. It didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it was going to be a big deal, except that the schedule was only accommodating if you were in the Pacific Northwest. The first reboot took out a secondary replica of our MongoDB database. Unfortunately &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongoid/moped/issues/321&#34;&gt;the driver handled that poorly&lt;/a&gt; and spent the first 400ms of every subsequent HTTP request trying to reconnect to the missing instance. That server came back up, but failed to find its storage volumes because of a human mistake in a past migration and the alerts were mistakenly silenced by someone monitoring the system. A few hours later the primary was being stepped down and rebooted, sending the driver into panic over &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mongoid/moped/issues/323&#34;&gt;another bug&lt;/a&gt;. The site went down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this was obvious while it was happening as the rate of automated alerts grew. Engineers communicated to the team that they are actively focusing on bringing the systems back up. This helped to fend off a large amount of instant messages, e-mails, texts and phone calls from various people on the team that were in the middle of demoing something to a very important prospective customer on the other side of the planet. It was also the middle of the night in New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that all the systems are back up, lets write a detailed outage post-mortem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a Security Bug Bounty Program at Artsy</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/09/24/launching-a-security-bug-bounty-program-at-artsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/09/24/launching-a-security-bug-bounty-program-at-artsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many established companies have bug bounty programs, including a recently publicized &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2014/09/10/bug-bounty-programs&#34;&gt;Twitter Bug Bounty&lt;/a&gt;. Some use services, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackerone.com&#34;&gt;HackerOne&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugcrowd.com&#34;&gt;BugCrowd&lt;/a&gt;. In early September 2014 we quietly launched &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.net/security&#34;&gt;our own Security Bug Bounty&lt;/a&gt;. Since then we have fixed 14 issues reported by 15 security researchers and paid $750 in bounty. In the process we have learned a ton and wanted to share some things that would have probably done a little bit differently, knowing what we know now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will focus on both technical and non-technical takeaways, and will provide an extensive list of vulnerabilities that should have been dealt with before launching our bug bounty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>