<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Artsy Engineering</title>
    <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Artsy Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking - Part 2: Where To Start?</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/03/14/public-speaking-part2-where-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/03/14/public-speaking-part2-where-to-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/&#34;&gt;you’d like to give speaking a go&lt;/a&gt;, or perhaps you were always interested. By now you’re probably wondering where to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are various options depending on what you’re looking for. Would you prefer a smaller, intimate audience or would you like to reach far and wide? Is the topic of your choice suited for a quick talk or would you rather discuss it at length? Let’s have a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking - Part 1: Is It For Me?</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Artsy, sharing knowledge is heavily encouraged and so we write our code in the open, document using blog posts, and speak about our experiences. Many have &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/qnoid/status/702955785064677376&#34;&gt;bumped into us&lt;/a&gt; at various places around the world. And so I often get the question: “How did you get started? I’m interested in speaking too”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the name of sharing experiences with others, I can’t encourage this enough. Unfortunately though, public speaking is still considered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/10/30/clowns-are-twice-as-scary-to-democrats-as-they-are-to-republicans/&#34;&gt;man’s biggest fear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to share with you the benefits of public speaking, tips on how to get started, and how to give great presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Lab</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/10/peer-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/10/peer-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was living in Amsterdam, I participated in plenty of &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsterdam.rs&#34;&gt;Appsterdam&lt;/a&gt; events. Things like the weekly Meeten en Drinken. I even helped lead a class in Swift. One of the events I liked the most was called Peer Lab, organized every Saturday morning by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/samuelgoodwin&#34;&gt;Samuel Goodwin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of Peer Lab is pretty simple, but also somewhat profound: developers gather in a physical space to work on things. If someone has a question, they ask the group. If you can help, you offer assistance. The goal is to foster a collaborative learning environment where everyone feels fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>