<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uikit on Artsy Engineering</title>
    <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/uikit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uikit on Artsy Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/uikit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective: Swift at Artsy</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/images/swift-in-rn/swift-in-react-native.svg&#34; style=&#34;width:300px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swift became public in June 2014, by August we had started using it in Artsy. By October, we had &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/&#34;&gt;Swift in production&lt;/a&gt; channelling hundreds of thousands of dollars in auction bids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is pretty obvious that Swift is the future of native development on Apple platforms. It was a no-brainer to then build an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/emergence&#34;&gt;Apple TV app&lt;/a&gt; in Swift, integrated Swift-support into our key app Eigen and built non-trivial parts of that &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/&#34;&gt;application in Swift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first started experimenting with React Native in February 2016, and by August 2016, we announced that &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2016/08/15/React-Native-at-Artsy/&#34;&gt;Artsy moved to React Native&lt;/a&gt; effectively meaning new code would be in JavaScript from here onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re regularly asked &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; we moved, and it was touched on briefly in our announcement but I&amp;rsquo;d like to dig in to this and try to cover a lot of our decision process. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re into understanding why a small team of iOS developers with decades of native experience switched to JavaScript, read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will cover: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/#What.are.Artsy.s.apps.&#34;&gt;What are Artsy&amp;rsquo;s apps?&lt;/a&gt;, Swifts &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/#Swift.s.upsides&#34;&gt;positives&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/#Native.Downsides&#34;&gt;negatives&lt;/a&gt; for us, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/#React.Native&#34;&gt;React Native&lt;/a&gt;, and our &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2017/02/05/Retrospective-Swift-at-Artsy/#React.Native..one.year.later&#34;&gt;1-year summary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Chairs</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2013/03/29/musical-chairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2013/03/29/musical-chairs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Artsy we make Artsy Folio. Folio is an awesome portfolio app that shows our gallery and museum partners their artworks in one place, allows them to easily get information about their inventory and to send works by email to their contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folio has to deal with large multi-gigabyte syncs in order to operate offline. That makes for a great user experience, but for the developer working on the sync, it&amp;rsquo;s not as pleasant. Combined with our use of Core Data, the app’s maturity, and dealing with data store migrations, things can get hairy. We needed a tool that could freeze and restore app data at will, obviating the need for constant syncing and resyncing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I built &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/chairs&#34;&gt;chairs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Making It Personal in iOS with Searchbars</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/05/11/on-making-it-personal--in-iOS-with-searchbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/05/11/on-making-it-personal--in-iOS-with-searchbars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We make Folio, a pretty kick-ass iPad app that we give away to our partners to showcase their inventory at art fairs. Whilst making it we tried to ensure that all of the application fits in with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.net&#34;&gt;Artsy&lt;/a&gt; website aesthetic, and recently the last natively styled control fell to our mighty code hammers. That was the &lt;code&gt;UISearchBar&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ortastuff.s3.amazonaws.com/images/custom_searchbar_example.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Artsy Folio&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When displaying only search results in a table it makes a lot of sense to use Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;UISearchDisplayController&lt;/code&gt; as it handles a lot of edge cases for you. However the downside is that you lose some control over how the views interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search bar was the only native control that actually made it into the version 1 release. This was mainly due to it requiring a bit of black magic in order to get it to work the way we wanted. So lets go through the code and rip it to pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>