<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Auctions on Artsy Engineering</title>
    <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/auctions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Auctions on Artsy Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/auctions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tech Behind Live Auction Integration</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late June, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/auctions/&#34;&gt;Artsy auctions&lt;/a&gt; team launched our Live Auction Integration (LAI) product. It allows people to participate online in live sales held at auction houses &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/auction-partnerships&#34;&gt;that partner with Artsy&lt;/a&gt;. It was a big project, begun in December, involving both brand new software and extensive integration work with the rest of our systems. This is the first in what will be a series of blog posts discussing the engineering work we did to get a complex product from inception to launch in such a brief time window, with a go-live deadline set in stone weeks in advance. In this, I’ll dig into what we shipped on a high level, as well as some of the overarching technical decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an English Auction with MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/04/17/building-an-english-auction-with-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/04/17/building-an-english-auction-with-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artsy ran several successful auctions over the past few months. The first, &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.net/feature/two-x-two&#34;&gt;TWO x TWO&lt;/a&gt;, raised hundreds of thousands of dollars for amfAR (the AIDS Research foundation), and the Dallas Museum of Art. It was followed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.net/feature/ici-benefit-auction&#34;&gt;Independent Curators International&lt;/a&gt;, at which Artsy launched on-site auction projection screens, which displayed competing bids coming in online from places around the world, like Oslo and Santa Monica, in realtime. Users could place bids on the website, via the iPhone app or with one of the Artsy representatives in the room carrying an iPad.  All the auction lots sold, and Artsy helped ICI to raise 50% more than its target revenue goal. Other, recent Artsy auctions include &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.net/feature/public-art-fund-2014-spring-benefit&#34;&gt;Public Art Fund&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.net/feature/brooklyn-artists-ball&#34;&gt;Brooklyn Artists Ball&lt;/a&gt;, benefitting the Brooklyn Museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/images/2014-04-17-implementing-bidding-in-an-english-auction-with-mongodb/ici-live-auction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ICI Auction: Live&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The domain of auctions is a fascinating one, and includes everything from buying items on eBay to trading livestock and selling investment products on the stock exchange. For those interested in the large spectrum of auctions I highly recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sci.brooklyn.cuny.edu/~parsons/projects/mech-design/publications/bluffers-final.pdf&#34;&gt;Auctions and bidding: A guide for computer
scientists&lt;/a&gt; by Simon Parsons (CUNY), Juan A. Rodriguez-Aguilar (CSIC) and Mark Klein (MIT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Artsy we implemented a classic English auction with, so called, &amp;ldquo;book bids&amp;rdquo;. I spent a fair amount of time visiting engineering teams that have built internet auctions, most of which were transactional systems where taking a position on an item involved starting a transaction, running an auction round and committing the changes. In contrast, we chose to deliver a simpler, eventually consistent system on top of MongoDB, in which all data is immutable and where some level of serialization occurs within a single background process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll go over some data modeling and examine the auction engine implementation details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>