<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juniors on Artsy Engineering</title>
    <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/juniors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Juniors on Artsy Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/juniors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Help! I&#39;m becoming Post-Junior</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/10/10/Help-Im-becoming-Post-Junior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/10/10/Help-Im-becoming-Post-Junior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived in NYC for 2 years now. I’ve been around long enough that some of the people I helped when they started learning have begun to feel like they’re not “Juniors” anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have begun feeling confident in their code, their responsibilities at the company and wanting to improve both. It&amp;rsquo;s a feeling that maybe, just maybe, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ashfurrow.com/blog/normalizing-struggle/&#34;&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re not struggling to stay afloat anymore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post aims to be technology-agnostic, and if you sit somewhere at 1.5 - 3 years of programming experience then you’ll probably get something out of it. On top of that,  I’ll give some pragmatic JS and iOS specific tips at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing, applying and getting your first job in iOS</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/30/iOS-Junior-Interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/30/iOS-Junior-Interviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was at the beginning of my career, my first developer job application was to a design agency who were doing Mac development too. It was pretty nerve-wracking to apply for my first programming job, and I came into the interview with no idea what to expect. I had just graduated from university and was at the first few steps of my career, I&amp;rsquo;d call this being a junior. It was a time period where I would need mentoring, and supervision in order to grow. A good explanation is in &lt;a href=&#34;http://programmers.stackexchange.com/questions/14914/whats-the-difference-between-entry-level-jr-sr-developers&#34;&gt;this StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;m both further on in my career, and involved with so many juniors in NYC, I&amp;rsquo;m meeting with a lot of people who are in the same position I was then and I get a lot of questions asking what they can do to prepare. This post &lt;em&gt;attempts&lt;/em&gt; at being a comprehensive collection of recommendations. It is subjective, of course, and strongly biased towards my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I jump through to the article, there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that should be above the fold. &lt;em&gt;Chill out&lt;/em&gt;. You might not get it right on the first try, I&amp;rsquo;ve applied for jobs and received a &amp;ldquo;no thanks.&amp;rdquo; Yet eventually I became the head of mobile at Artsy. Everyone finds their place in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>