<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ios on Artsy Engineering</title>
    <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ios on Artsy Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/categories/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying your app on a weekly basis via fastlane &#43; Travis CI</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a few apps now, but one of them isn&amp;rsquo;t really used by anyone other than developers. This is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/emission/tree/master/Example&#34;&gt;our React Native host app&lt;/a&gt;. We built our React Native components &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2016/08/24/On-Emission/&#34;&gt;as a library&lt;/a&gt; to be consumed by our other apps. Our development environment for these components is a unique app that acts as a host for the React Native components. It&amp;rsquo;s effectively a long tableview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is often updated for developers, but never deployed to beta users inside Artsy. So I automated it. Using Travis CI and fastlane. This post covers how I got that set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Retrospectives</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/05/17/ios-retrospectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/05/17/ios-retrospectives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1990s, Harvard researcher Amy Edmonson made the unexpected discovery that in hospitals, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/250959492_Learning_from_Mistakes_Is_Easier_Said_Than_Done_Group_and_Organizational_Influences_on_the_Detection_and_Correction_of_Human_Error&#34;&gt;higher performing teams reported making more mistakes&lt;/a&gt;. This is unexpected because one would assume that &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; performers would make &lt;em&gt;fewer&lt;/em&gt; mistakes. In fact, the number of mistakes isn&amp;rsquo;t what distinguishes higher-performing teams, but rather it&amp;rsquo;s their attitude towards discussing – and learning from – their failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past eight months reading more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychological_safety&#34;&gt;psychological safety&lt;/a&gt;: the shared belief that team members won&amp;rsquo;t be punished for speaking up with mistakes or questions or ideas. As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to operationalize psychological safety on my own team, and part of that includes discussing and learning from our mistakes. At Artsy, we candidly discuss site outages or production bugs on the web, but haven&amp;rsquo;t historically been great at communicating about iOS problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to start doing more retrospectives after things go wrong. So this week, I held my first iOS retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is fastlane match?</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/04/05/what-is-fastlane-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/04/05/what-is-fastlane-match/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like anyone working on a non-trivial app in the iOS world who values their time, we use fastlane. &lt;a href=&#34;https://fastlane.tools&#34;&gt;fastlane&lt;/a&gt; is a suite
of tools that makes it much simpler to automate the very manual processes provided by Apple for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve adopted it in a relatively piece-meal manner in different projects, converting custom in-house code to something
provided by the gem.  Over time we found what pieces of the suite work for us. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/energy/pull/266&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted another today&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/match&#34;&gt;match&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;match automates setting up your iOS projects for code signing. One of the most arduous orthogonal tasks which every dev team learns and then forgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In using match, we have given away a bit of control with code signing, and so this post is going to dig into; what we used
to have, and how it works now with match instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xcode 8 Manual Codesigning with Fastlane</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/01/13/xcode-8-fastlane-codesigning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2017/01/13/xcode-8-fastlane-codesigning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New year, new deploy process! Late last year our mobile team completed the update to Swift 3 (and thus, the update to Xcode 8). The latest version of Apple&amp;rsquo;s IDE includes a lovely feature: automating provisioning profile management! (Note: not sarcasm, the feature is really nice. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2016/401/&#34;&gt;WWDC video&lt;/a&gt; for an in-depth exploration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/images/2017-01-13-xcode-8-fastlane-codesigning/xcode-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Automatic code signing settings&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I went to make our first &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/12/15/Automating-Testflight-Deploys/&#34;&gt;automated deploy&lt;/a&gt; today, things didn&amp;rsquo;t work; I got a somewhat cryptic error about code signing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing the app&#39;s Source Code from your Simulator</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/10/14/Accessing-the-Source-Code-from-your-Simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/10/14/Accessing-the-Source-Code-from-your-Simulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months twice I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to access the source code of our application. The first time I did it I came up with a pretty neat hack, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really work in many places. The second time however, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/orta/status/786470282093625344&#34;&gt;asked the internet&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/saniul/status/786470857635827712&#34;&gt;internet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/0xced/status/786619335116750848&#34;&gt;replied&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TLDR: You can use your &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/350/commits/2a39c743bcaaf2e3b848ad60621198f40365fdd2&#34;&gt;project&amp;rsquo;s scheme&lt;/a&gt; to expose derived Xcode environment variables to your source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the blog post is a little bit about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I wanted to do that and what I did with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Swift at Artsy, Beginners Lesson Three</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/30/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/30/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;rsquo;re back! With lesson three of the beginners&amp;rsquo; Swift-at-Artsy course. To recap, Orta and I &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/&#34;&gt;led a course at Artsy&lt;/a&gt; to teach our colleagues Swift &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; August, and we&amp;rsquo;re doing it again. I&amp;rsquo;m leading the stream for people who&amp;rsquo;ve never programmed before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was lesson three and I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/e2ErzD8ibG8&#34;&gt;screen recording&lt;/a&gt; of my walkthrough of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Swift-at-Artsy/tree/master/Beginners/Lesson%20Three&#34;&gt;the material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Swift at Artsy, Beginners Lesson Two</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/23/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/23/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;rsquo;re back! With lesson two of the beginners&amp;rsquo; Swift-at-Artsy course. To recap, Orta and I &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/&#34;&gt;led a course at Artsy&lt;/a&gt; to teach our colleagues Swift &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; August, and we&amp;rsquo;re doing it again. I&amp;rsquo;m leading the stream for people who&amp;rsquo;ve never programmed before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was lesson two and I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/EBtzqx1YRBg&#34;&gt;screen recording&lt;/a&gt; of my walkthrough of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Swift-at-Artsy/tree/master/Beginners/Lesson%20Two&#34;&gt;the material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Swift at Artsy, Beginners Lesson One</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/15/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/08/15/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last August, Orta and I &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/&#34;&gt;led a course at Artsy&lt;/a&gt; to teach our colleagues Swift. There were two parallel groups of learners: a &amp;ldquo;beginners&amp;rdquo; group who had never coded before, and an &amp;ldquo;informed&amp;rdquo; group who already knew how to code. This year, we&amp;rsquo;re leading the course again with a slight twist: we&amp;rsquo;re repeating the course for absolute beginners, and we&amp;rsquo;re introduce a new course for anyone who completed last year&amp;rsquo;s beginner course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re really excited both to help new colleagues take their first steps into programming, and to help returning colleagues continue their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was lesson one of the beginner group, and I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/OLdSg0XpFqA&#34;&gt;screen recording&lt;/a&gt; of my walkthrough of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Swift-at-Artsy/tree/master/Beginners/Lesson%20One&#34;&gt;lesson one&amp;rsquo;s material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review: Energy Sync</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/02/12/Code-Review-Energy-Sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/02/12/Code-Review-Energy-Sync/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are slowly trying to do high-level code-review views for all of our iOS apps. So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/&#34;&gt;Emergence&lt;/a&gt; and now &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/&#34;&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;. This is the second part of the Energy code review. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/&#34;&gt;first part&lt;/a&gt; covers the the critical codepaths that go from the App&amp;rsquo;s launch to sending an email, which is the main use-case for the app. This video covers how Folio does sync between the Artsy API and the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sync is a complex problem. This video covers our old techniques, how we changed them, the underlying abstractions we use now and how we can test each component individually. It&amp;rsquo;s an hour long, and it&amp;rsquo;s a little computer-sciencey. So I think people who have shipped some small apps would get a lot out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=05HaKChPe_g&#34;&gt;to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review: Energy overview</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are slowly trying to do high-level code-review views for all of our iOS apps. So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/&#34;&gt;Emergence&lt;/a&gt;. Folio is an app that&amp;rsquo;s shipped to the App Store in early 2012, it&amp;rsquo;s used by our Partners to showcase their works offline, at fairs and on the go. If you want the full spiel, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://folio.artsy.net&#34;&gt;this microsite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video talks through a lot of the critical codepaths that go from the App&amp;rsquo;s launch to sending an email, which is the main use-case for the app. We have another video coming up which exclusively covers how Folio does sync between the Artsy API and the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xhd25hFzN4o&#34;&gt;to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing, applying and getting your first job in iOS</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/30/iOS-Junior-Interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/30/iOS-Junior-Interviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was at the beginning of my career, my first developer job application was to a design agency who were doing Mac development too. It was pretty nerve-wracking to apply for my first programming job, and I came into the interview with no idea what to expect. I had just graduated from university and was at the first few steps of my career, I&amp;rsquo;d call this being a junior. It was a time period where I would need mentoring, and supervision in order to grow. A good explanation is in &lt;a href=&#34;http://programmers.stackexchange.com/questions/14914/whats-the-difference-between-entry-level-jr-sr-developers&#34;&gt;this StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;m both further on in my career, and involved with so many juniors in NYC, I&amp;rsquo;m meeting with a lot of people who are in the same position I was then and I get a lot of questions asking what they can do to prepare. This post &lt;em&gt;attempts&lt;/em&gt; at being a comprehensive collection of recommendations. It is subjective, of course, and strongly biased towards my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I jump through to the article, there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that should be above the fold. &lt;em&gt;Chill out&lt;/em&gt;. You might not get it right on the first try, I&amp;rsquo;ve applied for jobs and received a &amp;ldquo;no thanks.&amp;rdquo; Yet eventually I became the head of mobile at Artsy. Everyone finds their place in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Good OSS Citizen</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/28/being-a-good-open-source-citizen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/28/being-a-good-open-source-citizen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the day in the life of an open source citizen: me. On our app, I was given &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eigen/issues/971&#34;&gt;an issue&lt;/a&gt; that would allow users to refine what kinds of sale artworks they were looking at, and it included this &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; slider control so they could set min/max price ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Swift at Artsy</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the Artsy engineering team includes many disciplines, tech stacks, and personalities, we all share a few things in common: a respect for each other, an appreciation of art-meets-science, and a celebration of learning. These are actually traits shared with our entire company, even non-engineers. So last Summer when Orta and I had some down time, it occurred to us how we could do something super-productive that was congruent with our values: we could teach the company Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review: Eidolon</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt; is the third app from Artsy&amp;rsquo;s mobile team, and it was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/&#34;&gt;first to be developed totally in the open&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s often used as a reference for what an app written in Swift, or written using FRP, should look like. Given how interested the community seems to be around the app, it&amp;rsquo;s about time we did a walkthrough of the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating TestFlight Deploys using Fastlane</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/12/15/Automating-Testflight-Deploys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/12/15/Automating-Testflight-Deploys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a really &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/18/Cocoa-Architecture-Dependencies/&#34;&gt;strong supporter&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fastlane.tools&#34;&gt;fastlane&lt;/a&gt; toolset. I think it fixes a lot of common developer problems, in a space that Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t really touch. The command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve added hints of fastlane to our apps at different rates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt; uses fastlane for everything but &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eigen/&#34;&gt;Eigen&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/energy&#34;&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/emergence&#34;&gt;Emergence&lt;/a&gt; have been pretty slow on the uptake, though they have more complicated setups, being App Store apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;https://krausefx.com/&#34;&gt;Felix&lt;/a&gt; announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://krausefx.com/blog/introducing-match-a-new-approach-to-code-signing&#34;&gt;match&lt;/a&gt; this week, I felt like he tackled a problem we face in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.net/job/mobile-engineer&#34;&gt;small dev team&lt;/a&gt;. I integrated this, only to find that it could also fix my problems with deployment. The rest of this post goes into the &amp;ldquo;how I did this.&amp;rdquo; You can also cheat and look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eigen/compare/d06270882aadec8f03927455a5229b53dd0a73c8...9eaf9082ebdcdf75f12ad2804260587e01526f2d&#34;&gt;commits&lt;/a&gt; directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Licenses for OSS Code</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/12/11/License-and-You/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/12/11/License-and-You/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of our internal Lunch and Learn series, I  gave a talk to our developers with an overview of the different types of source code licenses available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always recommend MIT within Artsy, but understanding what the other ones are and &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/01/29/how-art-dot-sy-uses-github-to-build-art-dot-sy/&#34;&gt;why we made&lt;/a&gt; the choices we have done is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0r7JcN3Q_LY&#34;&gt;to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview, as well as all of the speakers notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to RxSwift</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/12/08/reactive-cocoa-to-rxswift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/12/08/reactive-cocoa-to-rxswift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/&#34;&gt;built Eidolon last year&lt;/a&gt;, Swift was still pre-1.0 and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t rely on the wide variety of available Swift libraries we enjoy today. I wanted to build it using functional reactive programming, because that&amp;rsquo;s how I believe &lt;a href=&#34;https://realm.io/news/altconf-ash-furrow-functional-reactive-swift/&#34;&gt;everyone should write software&lt;/a&gt;, but there were no Swift-based FRP libraries at the time. As a compromise, I used ReactiveCocoa&amp;rsquo;s Objective-C API (the Swift API was months away from an alpha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review: Emergence</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We released the fourth app from the mobile team, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Emergence/&#34;&gt;Emergence&lt;/a&gt;, on day one for the new Apple TV and are currently getting around 2k downloads a day. The codebase was created by a single developer, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to keep that knowledge siloed. So, I ran an hour long code review session last night where I talked through the codebase, explained why some decisions were made and about the differences between tvOS and UIKit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I had been asked to write a blog post about tvOS in general, I felt that making the code review public for anyone to watch would be a nice alternative to the usual long-form writing on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NErVWhEzIBM&#34;&gt;to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Offline More</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/30/Work-Offline-More/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/30/Work-Offline-More/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to know what I love writing in a pull request? &lt;em&gt;Sorry this is such a big PR, but I was working offline…&lt;/em&gt; It is one of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Emergence/pull/23&#34;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Emergence/pull/39&#34;&gt;key&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Emergence/pull/45&#34;&gt;reasons&lt;/a&gt; I managed to get our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/emergence&#34;&gt;Artsy Shows TV&lt;/a&gt; app released ahead of schedule with a looming unknown App Store &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Emergence/issues?q=milestone%3A%221.0+Ship+to+Apple%22&#34;&gt;deadline&lt;/a&gt;. Offering more time for polish like thumbnail image &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/Emergence/compare/84855a310d47e071419b52b78978d14d751ec4e0...40966752111a309a20b4878e00a1c8e27cb53261&#34;&gt;pre-caching&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last week before shipping I was scheduled to get a H1B VISA stamp for my passport, which means a trip to London. London is basically a &lt;strong&gt;million&lt;/strong&gt; miles away from where I occasionally live in Huddersfield. So I opted for a coach. On the 5 and a half hours of travel, I had gone from behind schedule to feature complete prototype. On the way back, I had started to remove the word prototype from what we were looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; optimise to work offline on every iOS project. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips on how we do it in all our apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVVM in Swift</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/24/mvvm-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/24/mvvm-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Model View ViewModel has become the default way I write apps on iOS – it makes writing iOS apps a joy. I&amp;rsquo;ve written &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.objc.io/issues/13-architecture/mvvm/&#34;&gt;about it&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teehanlax.com/blog/model-view-viewmodel-for-ios/&#34;&gt;again&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/ashfurrow/reactivecocoa-at-mdevcon-2014&#34;&gt;again&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/iosfrp&#34;&gt;oh my&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But last Autumn, as our team was all-hands-on-deck to wrap up the &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/&#34;&gt;auctions kiosk app&lt;/a&gt;, we chose not to use MVVM. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were building a &lt;em&gt;new app&lt;/em&gt; in a &lt;em&gt;new language&lt;/em&gt; using a &lt;em&gt;non-Swift framework&lt;/em&gt; for functional reactive programming. I was also teaching colleagues what they needed to know about ReactiveCocoa to help write the app. We used the MVC pattern because the relative cost of MVVM was too high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa Architecture: Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/18/Cocoa-Architecture-Dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/18/Cocoa-Architecture-Dependencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of going through the design patterns we&amp;rsquo;ve found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk a bit about some of
the way in which we decide our apps dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think of your dependencies as being things in your Podfile, but it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more nuanced than that. The tools you use for development, deployment, testing and external integrations are all things in which you depend on others to make your app work. I&amp;rsquo;d like to look into the hows and the whys of the decisions we&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugomore42&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mobile team of is a collection of smart people; we aim to work with people who have different opinions, and different backgrounds. This means we often don&amp;rsquo;t agree on project direction but moving forwards is about finding compromise. Every technical project within Artsy has a de-facto leader, and they get to make the call at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa Architecture: Dropped Design Patterns</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/01/Cocoa-Architecture-Dropped-Design-Patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/09/01/Cocoa-Architecture-Dropped-Design-Patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of going through the design patterns we&amp;rsquo;ve found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk a bit about some of the patterns that we&amp;rsquo;ve had and migrated away from. This is not 100% comprehensive, as there has been a lot of time, and a lot of people involved. Instead I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and give a birds eye view, and zoom in on some things that feel more important overall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Trek 2: The Wrath of count()</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/27/swift-trek-2-the-wrath-of-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/27/swift-trek-2-the-wrath-of-count/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday at our mobile practice standup, I mentioned that I was in-between projects and looking for something to do. Orta suggested migrating Eidolon, the Artsy bidding kiosk app, to Swift 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our CI is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/pull/466&#34;&gt;broken anyway&lt;/a&gt;, so now is the perfect opportunity to make changes that would break CI. Additionally, Swift 2 seems to have more-or-less stabilized in the latest betas, so we don&amp;rsquo;t expect many gotchas leading up to the GM. Finally, this is an enterprise-distributed app, so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about submitting to the App Store using betas of Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Swift 2 it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa Architecture: Hybrid Apps</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/24/Cocoa-Architecture-Hybrid-Apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/24/Cocoa-Architecture-Hybrid-Apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of going through the design patterns we&amp;rsquo;ve found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk a bit about &lt;em&gt;Hybrid Applications&lt;/em&gt;. A hybrid application refers to an app that uses native code and web content intertwined. Our flagship iOS app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eigen&#34;&gt;eigen&lt;/a&gt; is a hybrid app, and it seems to get more and more hybrid-y each release. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk a little bit about the pros and cons of this approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugomore42&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-hybrid-app&#34;&gt;What is a Hybrid App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is the widest possible definition above, so let&amp;rsquo;s dig in as this can be a contentious. There is a whole spectrum of which an app can be classed as a hybrid app. This ranges from more or less web-tech everywhere to 100% native code like Objective-C / Swift.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa Architecture: ARSwitchboard</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/19/Cocoa-Architecture-Switchboard-Pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/19/Cocoa-Architecture-Switchboard-Pattern/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa Architecture: ARRouter</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture-Router-Pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture-Router-Pattern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about a pattern that we&amp;rsquo;ve been using for the last few years on the Artsy Mobile team. This pattern pre-dates me joining Artsy by a few weeks, and was introduced into our codebase by &lt;a href=&#34;http://90wpm.com&#34;&gt;Ben Jackson&lt;/a&gt;, this was the &lt;code&gt;ARRouter&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s first method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objc&#34;&gt;  + (NSURL *)newOAuthURLWithUsername:(NSString *)username password:(NSString *)password {
      NSDictionary *params = [[NSDictionary alloc] initWithObjectsAndKeys:
                              username, @&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,
                              password, @&amp;quot;password&amp;quot;,
                              ARAuthClientID, @&amp;quot;client_id&amp;quot;,
                              ARAuthSecret, @&amp;quot;client_secret&amp;quot;,
                              @&amp;quot;credentials&amp;quot;, @&amp;quot;grant_type&amp;quot;,
                              nil];
      NSString *url_string = [[NSString alloc] initWithFormat:@&amp;quot;%@%@&amp;quot;, AROAuthURL, [params queryString]];
      NSURL *url = [ARRouter newURLWithPath:url_string];
      [url_string release];
      [params release];
      return url;
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s pre-ARC, pre-Dictionary Literals, memory-managed code. We took this pattern and rolled with it for the next 4 years, this article is about where we&amp;rsquo;ve taken it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within Eigen, &lt;code&gt;ARRouter&lt;/code&gt; is one of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/904e8abfc11ce6ea4b6e81f0e02684b755a280c3/Artsy/Networking/ARRouter.m&#34;&gt;biggest classes&lt;/a&gt;, coming in at almost 1,000 lines of code. Whereas in Energy, it sits at a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/e51529250ede359c781042f222d5836eb9e8a979/Classes/Util/App/ARRouter.m&#34;&gt;more reasonable&lt;/a&gt; 300 lines. Eidolon does not have an ARRouter, what gives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Lab</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/10/peer-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/10/peer-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was living in Amsterdam, I participated in plenty of &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsterdam.rs&#34;&gt;Appsterdam&lt;/a&gt; events. Things like the weekly Meeten en Drinken. I even helped lead a class in Swift. One of the events I liked the most was called Peer Lab, organized every Saturday morning by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/samuelgoodwin&#34;&gt;Samuel Goodwin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of Peer Lab is pretty simple, but also somewhat profound: developers gather in a physical space to work on things. If someone has a question, they ask the group. If you can help, you offer assistance. The goal is to foster a collaborative learning environment where everyone feels fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Sourcing Energy</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Artsy Mobile team is pretty aggressive in our stance on &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.dblock.org/2015/02/09/becoming-open-source-by-default.html&#34;&gt;Open Source by Default&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ve talked about it at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DvDeEZ0NDw&amp;amp;spfreload=10&#34;&gt;conferences&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjjvnrqDjpM&#34;&gt;around&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zPbLYWmLPow&#34;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/orta/ios-at-artsy&#34;&gt;world&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.objc.io/issues/22-scale/artsy&#34;&gt;renowned magazines&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/&#34;&gt;our blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that we don&amp;rsquo;t just talk externally about Open Source. Internally, the Mobile team runs talks about Open Source for the rest of the Artsy staff. As well, we discuss the tooling and business implications of having our work in public repos. Artsy strives for an open culture, in this case the development team, on the whole, is just further along in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Source app idea started with an experiment in the Summer of 2014, asking, &amp;ldquo;What does a truly Open Source App look like?&amp;rdquo; The outcome of that was our Swift Kiosk app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt;. Open from day one. We took the knowledge from that and applied it to our public facing app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eigen/&#34;&gt;Eigen&lt;/a&gt;. Open from day 806. That made 2/3rds of our apps Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about our final app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/energy&#34;&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;. Open from day 1433 and ~3500 commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Write Unit Tests Like a Brood Parasite</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/07/06/how-to-write-unit-tests-like-a-brood-parasite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/07/06/how-to-write-unit-tests-like-a-brood-parasite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To a beginner, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ocmock.org/&#34;&gt;OCMock&lt;/a&gt; looks scary. The syntax is strange, the idea of stubbing seems complicated, and skirting around the need to use it at all times kind of works out for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objc&#34;&gt;[[[mock stub] // three brackets!!

[OCMockObject niceMockForClass:UINavigationItem.class]; // it has to be told to be nice?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this can be overwhelming for someone who just wants to write simple unit tests for a particular view controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you look into the specifics of OCMock, however, things get less terrifying really quickly. It is helpful to compare OCMock’s approach to stubbing to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/60553870&#34;&gt;behaviors of certain bird species&lt;/a&gt;. As always, the soothing voice of David Attenborough brings clarity and joy to even the most mundane puzzles of life’s journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Eigenstate of Mind</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/06/04/an-eigenstate-of-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/06/04/an-eigenstate-of-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior to starting at Artsy, I followed a few online tutorials on iOS development. But a simple application demonstrating how to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raywenderlich.com/85578/first-core-data-app-using-swift&#34;&gt;build a todo list&lt;/a&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t illustrate the nuances of a production codebase. Tutorials are an important learning tool for beginners, but can&amp;rsquo;t possibly prepare you for everything you would encounter within an application like Artsy&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to have a mentor at Artsy to help me get started, and I wrote this post to pass along the lessons I learned. This is meant to be a guide for iOS beginners to get to know an open source production codebase. I&amp;rsquo;ll cover the Xcode project organization and where to find things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we Open Source&#39;d Eigen</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was 95 days ago, and I was sitting before of my computer in NYC. I loaded my terminal, opened &lt;a href=&#34;https://taptalk.me&#34;&gt;TapTalk&lt;/a&gt; on my phone, tapped on my collegue &lt;a href=&#34;http://ashfurrow.com&#34;&gt;Ash&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; avatar and held my finger there. I paused, this moment was a long time, it was worth waiting. I switched the camera from my face to the screen with the terminal open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This moment was probably the most nervous I had been in years. It showed &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;. I said &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s happening.&amp;rdquo; I hit return. A new era in the Artsy mobile team had started. A few minutes later, I wrote this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-cards=&#34;hidden&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have open source’d the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/artsy&#34;&gt;@Artsy&lt;/a&gt; iOS app.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/c1SWtHmUgy&#34;&gt;https://t.co/c1SWtHmUgy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;🎉&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ørta (@orta) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/orta/status/558395611754819586&#34;&gt;January 22, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go over the process we went through to get to that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CocoaPods-Keys and CI</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/01/21/cocoapods-keys-and-CI/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/01/21/cocoapods-keys-and-CI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We built CocoaPods-Keys as a way to remove API keys and secrets from our source code. We use it to open up our code to the public, without leaking private details. One of the cool things about doing it this way was that we could all use different API keys stashed away in each developers Keychain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure we could run CI on our apps we came up with two different ways to use keys on CI. This post explains them both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CocoaPods and Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/01/04/cocoapods-and-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2015/01/04/cocoapods-and-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/&#34;&gt;retrospective on Eidolon&lt;/a&gt;, Artsy iOS codebases are often used as testbeds for new CocoaPods features. With Eidolon, we had the opportunity to try out CocoaPods&amp;rsquo; support for frameworks and Swift. This post is a look back at the month of using dependencies as dynamic frameworks instead of static libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close to the Metal: Debugging Our Hardware Problem</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/11/18/debugging-our-hardware-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/11/18/debugging-our-hardware-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, Artsy’s mobile team has been working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt;, a bidding kiosk for Artsy’s auctions platform. While we’ve written a &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/&#34;&gt;retrospective&lt;/a&gt; on the process of making Eidolon from the software side of things, we didn’t really touch on how our software is being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Bidding Kiosk for iOS in Swift</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Summer of 2014, we began developing a bidding kiosk for the Artsy auctions platform (code-named &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt;). Typically, the iOS team here at Artsy worked on two main apps: a &lt;a href=&#34;http://iphone.artsy.net&#34;&gt;consumer-facing iPhone app&lt;/a&gt; and an iPad app used by art galleries. For Eidolon, we followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/01/29/how-art-dot-sy-uses-github-to-build-art-dot-sy/&#34;&gt;Artsy’s standard practices&lt;/a&gt; for building our software and use GitHub issues as our canonical source for bug reports and feature requests. Many of the components used in our apps are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;, but the codebases themselves remain in private repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial planning for Eidolon began over the Summer. Our designer &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/katarinabatina&#34;&gt;Katarina&lt;/a&gt; had the main features sketched out. I was scheduled to work on it at first, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/orta&#34;&gt;Orta&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/1aurabrown&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt; joining me near the end of the project. We had a rough scope: the app would be able to list artworks at an auction and allow prospective bidders to learn more about these artworks. The user would be able to register to bid and place bids using the Kiosk, including credit card processing for identity-checking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparent Prerequisite Network Requests with Swift and ReactiveCocoa</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/09/18/transparent-prerequisite-network-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/09/18/transparent-prerequisite-network-requests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artsy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://developers.artsy.net&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; requires something called an &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.artsy.net/docs/authentication&#34;&gt;XApp
token&lt;/a&gt; in order to perform
requests. The token comes back with an expiry date, after which the token will
no longer work. A new token will have to be fetched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{
	&amp;quot;xapp_token&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;SOME_TOKEN&amp;quot;,
	&amp;quot;expires_in&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2014-09-19T12:22:21.570Z&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our previous iOS apps, tragically written in Objective-C, we have a lot of
code that looks like the following. &lt;code&gt;getXappTokenWithCompletion:&lt;/code&gt; checks to
make sure that there is a valid token. If there is, it invokes the completion
block immediately. Otherwise, it fetches a token, sets it in a static variable,
and then invokes the completion block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objc&#34;&gt;[ArtsyAPI getXappTokenWithCompletion:^(NSString *xappToken, NSDate *expirationDate) {
    [ArtsyAPI getSomething:^(NSDictionary *results) {
       // do something
    } failure:^(NSError *error) {
        // handle herror
    }];
}];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s kind of ugly. A better approach might be to embed the token-requesting
logic within the &lt;code&gt;getSomething:&lt;/code&gt; method. But that kind of sucks, since we&amp;rsquo;d have
to reproduce that logic for &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; network-accessing method. If we have ten
methods, that&amp;rsquo;s ten times we need to duplicate that logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon&#34;&gt;new app&lt;/a&gt; (written in Swift), we&amp;rsquo;re
using a network abstraction layer we&amp;rsquo;ve created called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AshFurrow/Moya&#34;&gt;Moya&lt;/a&gt;.
Moya sits on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Alamofire/Alamofire&#34;&gt;Alamofire&lt;/a&gt; and
provides an abstraction for API endpoints. Instead of having ten different
network-accessing methods, there is only &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; method to which you pass one of
the ten different possible &lt;code&gt;enum&lt;/code&gt; values. This means you have compile-time
safety in your networking code, but that&amp;rsquo;s not really what we&amp;rsquo;re here to talk
about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CocoaPods Caching with Travis CI</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/08/08/CocoaPods-Caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/08/08/CocoaPods-Caching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/taking-a-snapshot-with-second-curtain/&#34;&gt;Ash said earlier&lt;/a&gt; we like using Continuous Integration. Today I spent a large amount of time migrating us to use the new CocoaPods caching system in Travis CI. To make up for my lost time I&amp;rsquo;m passing on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and also showing how we do CI at Artsy with Objective-C apps. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in how we do it in Swift, you can just check &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/artsy/eidolon&#34;&gt;Eidolon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a Snapshot with Second Curtain</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/08/04/taking-a-snapshot-with-second-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/08/04/taking-a-snapshot-with-second-curtain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Artsy, we try hard to &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/orta/getting-eigen-out?slide=35&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt;
our iOS applications to ensure that we avoid regressions and have a clearly
defined spec of how our apps should look and behave. One of the core pieces of
our testing setup is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/ios-snapshot-test-case&#34;&gt;FBSnapshotTestCase&lt;/a&gt;,
a library written by Facebook to compare views at runtime with images of those
views that are known to be correct. If the images differ, the test fails. We
also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org&#34;&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt; for continuous integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, we&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing a friction between the developers on the iOS team
and the tools we&amp;rsquo;re using to test our apps: while Travis allows us to easily
access the logs of test runs, it can only indicate that a snapshot test failed,
not why it failed. That&amp;rsquo;s because the images that are compared are locked on
Travis&amp;rsquo; machine – we cannot access those images, so we can&amp;rsquo;t see the
differences. This is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; promblematic when the tests pass locally but fail
only on Travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artsy&#39;s first closed source Pod</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/06/20/artsys-first-closed-source-pod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/06/20/artsys-first-closed-source-pod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I joined Artsy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.dblock.org&#34;&gt;dB&lt;/a&gt; pitched me this idea: &lt;em&gt;Open source as default.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this to heart. I genuinely believe the idea behind the philosophy. It&amp;rsquo;s cool that our real product isn&amp;rsquo;t our implementations on the web or native but the data which powers it - &lt;a href=&#34;https://artsy.net/theartgenomeproject&#34;&gt;the Art Genome Project&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, I spend a bunch of time &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AshFurrow/ARCollectionViewMasonryLayout&#34;&gt;on&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dblock/ARASCIISwizzle&#34;&gt;open&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dblock/ios-snapshot-test-case-expecta&#34;&gt;sourcing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dblock/ARTiledImageView&#34;&gt;solid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dstnbrkr/DRBOperationTree&#34;&gt;abstractions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/ORSimulatorKeyboardAccessor&#34;&gt;from&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/ORStackView&#34;&gt;our&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/ARAnalytics&#34;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt;, always taking the opinion if something is used in more than one place, it should be open sourced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I pushed some libraries that were a bit different, read on to find out why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the Xcode Plugin Snapshots</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/06/17/building-the-xcode-plugin-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/06/17/building-the-xcode-plugin-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of guy who thinks better tooling means better outcomes. But when good tooling isn&amp;rsquo;t available, it&amp;rsquo;s time to build it yourself. It&amp;rsquo;s this attitude that lead to my work on &lt;a href=&#34;http://cocoadocs.org&#34;&gt;CocoaDocs.org&lt;/a&gt;, and then to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cocoapods.org&#34;&gt;CocoaPods.org&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; its documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to apply this to testing, and in order to pull this off I&amp;rsquo;ve had to extend Xcode to show off the results of failing tests in a more visual way. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;ve extended Xcode to show the results of failing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/ios-snapshot-test-case&#34;&gt;view tests&lt;/a&gt; in a more visual way by building &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/snapshots&#34;&gt;Snapshots for Xcode&lt;/a&gt;.  Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the process of building an Xcode plugin so you can do this too. Screw stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Core Data Migrations</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/06/11/testing-core-data-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/06/11/testing-core-data-migrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time I released a patch release for &lt;a href=&#34;http://orta.github.io/#folio-header-unit&#34;&gt;Artsy Folio&lt;/a&gt; it crashed instantly, on every install. Turns out I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand Core Data migrations, now a few years on I grok it better but I&amp;rsquo;ve still lived with the memories of that dark dark day. Because of this I&amp;rsquo;ve had an informal rule of testing migrations with all the old build of Folio &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.github.io/blog/2013/03/29/musical-chairs/&#34;&gt;using chairs&lt;/a&gt; the day before submitting to the app store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time round, I&amp;rsquo;ve made vast changes to the Core Data models but skipped the manual work. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Programming and ARAnalytics</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/05/06/aspect-oriented-programming-and-aranalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2014/05/06/aspect-oriented-programming-and-aranalytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Analytics are common in iOS applications. They help inform our decisions
about products. Since analytics are so common, Artsy developed a library called
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/ARAnalytics&#34;&gt;ARAnalytics&lt;/a&gt;. This library provides a
single interface to many different backend analytics providers, freeing
developers from having to write code for each of the providers that they&amp;rsquo;re
using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a typical view controller on iOS. View controllers on iOS
represent the glue code between models and views. When a model changes, the view
controller updates the appearance of the UI. Similarly, when the UI is
interacted with by the user, the view controller updates the model. This is the
core of any standard iOS application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say that a button is pressed. We&amp;rsquo;ll handle that interaction in a
method called &lt;code&gt;buttonWasPressed:&lt;/code&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll want to update our model, but also to
track the analytics event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objc&#34;&gt;- (void)buttonWasPressed:(id)sender
{
	self.model.hearted = YES;

	[ARAnalytics event:@&amp;quot;hearted&amp;quot;];
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple enough, but consider that the analytics tracking code doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall within
our definition of a view controller – the button handler just happens to be a
convenient place to put the tracking code. Also consider that &lt;em&gt;every single&lt;/em&gt;
button handler is going to have to have similar code implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;there-has-to-be-a-better-way&#34;&gt;There has to be a better way.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARAnalytics - Analytics for iOS Apps</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2013/04/10/aranalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2013/04/10/aranalytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In both my &lt;a href=&#34;http://orta.github.com&#34;&gt;personal apps&lt;/a&gt; and Artsy Folio, I&amp;rsquo;m always after a deeper understanding of how people use the app. There&amp;rsquo;s three ways to do this: ask users, watch users and track usage. I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about the third of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with quite a lot of analytics tools for the Artsy website, and it seemed fitting to do the same for our mobile app. We wanted the freedom to change the analytics tool without having to change the code, and so &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/orta/ARAnalytics&#34;&gt;ARAnalytics&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Chairs</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2013/03/29/musical-chairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2013/03/29/musical-chairs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Artsy we make Artsy Folio. Folio is an awesome portfolio app that shows our gallery and museum partners their artworks in one place, allows them to easily get information about their inventory and to send works by email to their contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folio has to deal with large multi-gigabyte syncs in order to operate offline. That makes for a great user experience, but for the developer working on the sync, it&amp;rsquo;s not as pleasant. Combined with our use of Core Data, the app’s maturity, and dealing with data store migrations, things can get hairy. We needed a tool that could freeze and restore app data at will, obviating the need for constant syncing and resyncing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I built &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orta/chairs&#34;&gt;chairs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perils of iOS user agent strings</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/10/18/the-perils-of-ios-user-agent-sniffing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/10/18/the-perils-of-ios-user-agent-sniffing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a great deal of misinformation on the web about detecting an
iPad or an iPhone in JavaScript. The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/a/4617648&#34;&gt;top answer on stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; -
and many &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sitepoint.com/identify-apple-iphone-ipod-ipad-visitors/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.askdavetaylor.com/detect_apple_iphone_user_web_site_server.html&#34;&gt;this technique&lt;/a&gt; - are all incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conventional wisdom is that iOS devices have a user agent for
Safari and a user agent for the UIWebView. This assumption is
incorrect as iOS apps can and do
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/a/8666438&#34;&gt;customize their user agent&lt;/a&gt;. The
main offender here is Facebook, whose iOS app alone accounts for about
1-3% of Artsy&amp;rsquo;s daily traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare these user agent strings from iOS devices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# iOS Safari
iPad: Mozilla/5.0 (iPad; CPU OS 5_1 like Mac OS X) AppleWebKit/534.46 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/5.1 Mobile/9B176 Safari/7534.48.3
iPhone: Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; CPU iPhone OS 5_0 like Mac OS X) AppleWebKit/534.46 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/5.1 Mobile/9A334 Safari/7534.48.3

# UIWebView
iPad: Mozilla/5.0 (iPad; CPU OS 5_1 like Mac OS X) AppleWebKit/534.46 (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile/98176
iPhone: Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; U; CPU iPhone OS 4_1 like Mac OS X; en-us) AppleWebKit/532.9 (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile/8B117

# Facebook UIWebView
iPad: Mozilla/5.0 (iPad; U; CPU iPhone OS 5_1_1 like Mac OS X; en_US) AppleWebKit (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile [FBAN/FBForIPhone;FBAV/4.1.1;FBBV/4110.0;FBDV/iPad2,1;FBMD/iPad;FBSN/iPhone OS;FBSV/5.1.1;FBSS/1; FBCR/;FBID/tablet;FBLC/en_US;FBSF/1.0]
iPhone: Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; U; CPU iPhone OS 5_1_1 like Mac OS X; ru_RU) AppleWebKit (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile [FBAN/FBForIPhone;FBAV/4.1;FBBV/4100.0;FBDV/iPhone3,1;FBMD/iPhone;FBSN/iPhone OS;FBSV/5.1.1;FBSS/2; tablet;FBLC/en_US]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Grid Thumbnails</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/09/13/on-grid-thumbnails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/09/13/on-grid-thumbnails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/images/2012-09-13-on-grid-thumbnails/grid.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artsy Folio, our free iPad app for Gallery Partners, had been in the App Store for a couple of weeks before the iPad with a Retina display was announced. This had been something we expected internally and felt the application would be ready. We had all our image assets available in &lt;em&gt;@2x&lt;/em&gt; versions and an image pipeline that would take scaling into account. With that in mind, we changed our artwork grid view to show a double resolution image. Finally, once we were happy that it worked fine on the simulator, we sent the build off to Apple for review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app passed review, and was Retina-ready before the actual release. But within hours of getting our hands on a real Retina iPad, we had to pull the app. This post will explain why, and what we did to work it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Our Objective-C Code Standards</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/08/14/on-objective-c-code-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/08/14/on-objective-c-code-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of Xcode 4.4 I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a look back at our existing code standards and tried to come up with something that is cleaner and more elegant. Here are a few of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve been using to modernize the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remove-private-method-declarations-and-use-class-extensions-to-add-ivars&#34;&gt;Remove private method declarations and use class extensions to add ivars.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First to get chopped by the deletion button are private method declarations. After Xcode 4.2 came out we took to using the class extension feature to add private method declarations at the top of implementation files. This was a nice way of keeping private methods out of the header files. Now that the compiler will check for pre-existing method signatures within the same object there&amp;rsquo;s no need to define their interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Making It Personal in iOS with Searchbars</title>
      <link>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/05/11/on-making-it-personal--in-iOS-with-searchbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hizkifw.github.io/artsy.github.io-hugo/2012/05/11/on-making-it-personal--in-iOS-with-searchbars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We make Folio, a pretty kick-ass iPad app that we give away to our partners to showcase their inventory at art fairs. Whilst making it we tried to ensure that all of the application fits in with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://artsy.net&#34;&gt;Artsy&lt;/a&gt; website aesthetic, and recently the last natively styled control fell to our mighty code hammers. That was the &lt;code&gt;UISearchBar&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ortastuff.s3.amazonaws.com/images/custom_searchbar_example.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Artsy Folio&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When displaying only search results in a table it makes a lot of sense to use Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;UISearchDisplayController&lt;/code&gt; as it handles a lot of edge cases for you. However the downside is that you lose some control over how the views interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search bar was the only native control that actually made it into the version 1 release. This was mainly due to it requiring a bit of black magic in order to get it to work the way we wanted. So lets go through the code and rip it to pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>